Alexander Burr

Email alex@alexburr.com
Web www alexburr.com

LinkedIn alexanderburr
GitHub alexburr

Dribbble pokealex **JSFiddle** alexburr

"Alex's technical knowledge of the web is outstanding. He is an expert on web standards, web content management, user interface design and development, social media, business process improvement, browser compatibility, and many other areas. He is equally adept working in both open-source and enterprise technologies and programming languages.

"Alex creates exceptional user experiences, helping stakeholders focus on goals and objectives before designing a web site which will meet user needs. He has a keen understanding of how to structure roles on a web project in order to achieve long-term success within the company, and is able to create models and visualizations supporting these perspectives."

-Zach Roth, Project Director, URMC

Competencies & Skills

Project management concepts: life cycle methodology, needs assessment and usability, information architecture, content strategy, SEO and conversion, and analytics

20+ years experience in web development, software engineering, and user interface design

Server-side programming: ASP.Net with C#, PHP, ColdFusion

Client-side templating: C#: Razor, Nancy, PHP: Smarty

Unit testing: xUnit.net with Moq, Jest

Web frameworks: ASP.Net MVC, Web API, CodeIgniter, ColdFusion

on Wheels

Content management: Umbraco, WordPress, Textpattern, and Cascade Server

Wireframing and design: Axure RP, Adobe Photoshop, Visio,

Balsamiq

Client-side frameworks: React, AngularJS

Database experience: SQL Server, MySQL

Version control: Git, Mercurial, Subversion, TFS

Environments: Windows/IIS and Linux/Apache

Experience

Software Engineer, Pharos Systems International

June 2012-April 2021

Full-stack development of cloud print management solution's AWS EC2-hosted web interface, with C#, jQuery, Kendo UI, and React, connecting to RESTful services.

Worked on new cross-vendor printer UI for HP, Ricoh and KM, with a new front-end custom built on TypeScript, and a RESTful service layer developed in C♯.

Maintained and expanded API microservices in .NET Framework and .NET Core hosted in AWS ECS.

Developed WPF user interfaces for printer discovery and software installation as well as customer entitlement.

Consulted for Product Management team on user experience and user interface design, providing both wireframing and prototyping of new features in web applications and printer UIs.

Led effort to standardize UI design components across engineering teams, developing standard stylesheet and icon libraries, as well as documentation and example applications.

Lead Web Developer, University of Rochester Medical Center

July 2010-June 2012

Led effort to develop an institution-wide IT system status portal, meeting with stakeholders to deliver UX proposals, and coordinating development effort with programming team.

Piloted new Content Management strategy for departmental intranet web sites, utilizing the Umbraco web content management platform, built in C♯ on ASP.NET.

Designed and developed web applications for use in various institutional business processes and workflows.

Built and managed SharePoint sites for various institutional departments and centers.

Senior Web Developer, University of Rochester Medical Center

September 2007-June 2010

Designed and developed enterprise-level and multiple department-level websites.

Production Manager, Cazbah

September 2004-September 2007

Managed a production team of two specialists, and designed/developed of multiple client e-commerce websites.

Web Developer, Element K

October 2003-December 2003

Developed co-brands for Element K's Learning Management Systems. Modified client-supplied content for use in the LMS.

Software Engineer, AHT

June 2000-July 2002

Developed web applications for print server management software and product licensing servers.

Additional Projects

Groove Juice Swing

Ongoing

Content author, designer and developer for this website for a dance instruction group. Also designer/developer for various event websites, including https://www.stompology.com.

Yehoodi

2009-2017

Designer/developer for this social website for a nationwide swing dance community. https://www.yehoodi.com

GitHub Projects

Ongoing

Multiple projects to assist in guitar playing, songwriting, bandleading, and crochet blanket pattern design, built on a variety of web technologies including React and HTML5. <u>alexburr.github.iohttps://alexburr.github.io/</u>

Education

Rochester Institute of Technology BS in Information Technology (May 2000)

References

Available upon request.